Guide to the Baruch Charney Vladeck Papers and Photographs TAM.037
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Baruch Charney Vladeck Papers and Photographs
1906-1958
1920-1938
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Vladeck, B. (Baruch), 1886-1938
Bromberg, May Vladeck
Bromberg, Charney
Heinrich, Amy Vladeck
TAM.037
14 Linear Feet in 8 records cartons, 10 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize flat boxes, and 4 oversize folders.
Baruch Charney Vladeck (1886-1938) was born in Russia and emerged as one of the leading figures of the U.S. Jewish socialist movement of the twentieth century. He was general manager of The Jewish Daily Forward from 1918 to 1938 and was elected to the New York City Board of Alderman and the City Council. The papers contain correspondence, the manuscript of a partial autobiography, addresses, debates, biographical material, reports, memos, press releases, personal and family papers, photographs, and printed material. Included is material relating to public housing, Jewish charitable and labor organizations such as ORT and the Jewish Labor Committee, the status of Jews in Nazi Germany, political campaigns, Socialist Party affairs and other political matters. Correspondents include Freidrich Adler, Sholem Asch, Victor and Meta Berger, Daniel Hoan, Louise Kautsky, Harry Laidler, Algernon Lee, Ramsey McDonald and Lillian Wald.
Other Finding Aids
A complete description of the collection is available in Tamiment Library Bulletin vol. 42 (November 1964).
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
Although his career was shortened by his untimely death at age 52, Baruch Charney Vladeck (1886-1938) emerged as one of the leading figures of the Jewish socialist movement of the twentieth century. He was born Baruch Charney in Dukora, a small village near Minsk, Russia in 1886. His mother, left a widow with six children at age thirty-five, hoped that Baruch and his brother Samuel would become rabbis. But they soon rebelled against the traditional yeshiva education and were caught up in the ferment of radical, secularizing ideas in Jewish cultural circles in Minsk. Young Charney was soon conducting classes for workers in a labor Zionist school. The Czarist police found some of his recommended reading too liberal and early in 1904 he was arrested and sentenced to six months in the Minsk jail.
On his release he joined the "Bund," a Jewish labor and socialist party affiliated with the Russian Social Democratic party. He spent the next four years in fugitive life as an organizer (under the pen name "Vladeck") until, fearful of arrest, he fled to the United States in 1908. For three years Vladeck toured the country, lecturing to Jewish and socialist groups and obtaining a wide first-hand acquaintance with America. In 1911 he married Clara Richman, and they eventually had three children, May, Stephen and William.
Settling in Philadelphia, Vladeck became, in 1912, manager of the Philadelphia edition of the New York Jewish Daily Forward, the largest and most influential Yiddish daily in the United States. While in Philadelphia he studied economics and English at the University of Pennsylvania, and became an American citizen in 1915.
During World War I Vladeck emerged as a leaders in the Socialist Party of America. Moving in 1916 to New York City, he became city editor of the Forward, and only one year later he was one of a group of Socialists elected to the NYC Board of Aldermen. He was reelected in 1919 but lost his seat two years later when his district was gerrymandered. In the Socialist Party split of 1919 Vladeck energetically fought the Communist wing. In 1930 he ran unsuccessfully for Congress (8th District) on the Socialist ticket. Later in the 1930s, when the newly revitalized Socialist Party was again divided between Norman Thomas's left wing and a right wing led, after the death of Morris Hillquit, by Louis Waldman, Vladeck sought to play a mediating role. When the breach became final, he allied himself with the right wing and, together with David Dubinsky, became one of the founders of the American Labor Party.
Vladeck's early service on the NYC Board of Aldermen had quickened his interest in municipal housing, and in 1934 he was named by Mayor Fiorello La Guardia as a member of the New York City Housing Authority. This experience stood him in good stead when, in 1937, he was elected to the New York City Council on the ALP ticket. As majority leader of a labor anti-Tammany coalition in the Council, he initiated one of the first municipal slum-clearance projects in the country. In later tribute, New York named one of its great municipal projects the Vladeck Houses.
Meanwhile, as general manager of the Jewish Daily Forward, a post he held from 1918 until his death, and because of his own large gifts of oratory and persuasion, Vladeck had assumed a leading role in American Jewish life. He served as head of a number of organizations. In 1934 he founded and became first president of the Jewish Labor Committee, an umbrella group of Jewish labor and fraternal organizations which organized anti-Nazi activity in the U.S. and rescue and relief work for victims of fascism in Europe. Through his close ties with its president, William Green, he was able to induce the American Federation of Labor to endorse the anti-Nazi boycott and to set up a Labor Chest for the Relief and Liberation of the Workers of Europe. He also chaired the American ORT foundation.
A streak of revolutionary romanticism, a residue of his youth, always remained in Vladeck's character and showed itself most directly in his efforts to aid the daring underground operations in Germany, during the early days of Hitler's regime, of a group of dissident left-wing socialists known as the New Beginning. He called himself an "evolutionist rather than a revolutionist," and, although a lifelong Socialist, supported Franklin D. Roosevelt for president in 1936 and Fiorello La Guardia for mayor of New York in 1937.
Vladeck died of a coronary thrombosis on October 31, 1938. The affection in which he was held by the people of New York was demonstrated at his funeral, when over 50,000 persons massed in Rutgers Square, facing the Forward building, to hear funeral orations by Gov. Herbert Lehman, Senator Robert F. Wagner and other notables. Countless others lined the streets to view the cortege that bore his remains to Mt. Carmel Cemetery. The evolution of Vladeck's thought mirrors a similar adaptation by thousands of other socialists and radicals including the leaders of the large and powerful needle-trades unions. His career symbolizes the transformations wrought by American institutions on a European-shaped radicalism.
Sources:
Herling, John. "Baruch Charney Vladeck," American Jewish Yearbook 41 (1939-1940): 78-93.
Jonas, Franklin L. The Early Life and Career of B. Charney Vladeck. (Ph.D. dissertation, New York University, 1972).
Vladeck, Baruch Charney. B. Vladeck in Leben un Shafen. New York: Forverts, 1936.
Scope and Content Note
These papers document the life of Baruch Charney Vladeck, a leading figure of the U.S. Jewish socialist movement of the twentieth century. The papers contain correspondence, the manuscript of a partial autobiography, addresses, debates, biographical material, reports, memos, press releases, personal and family papers, photographs, audio recordings and printed material. Included is material relating to public housing, Jewish charitable and labor organizations such as ORT and the Jewish Labor Committee, the status of Jews in Nazi Germany, political campaigns, Socialist Party affairs, and other political matters. The majority of the collection is correspondence, and correspondents include Freidrich Adler, Sholem Asch, Victor and Meta Berger, Daniel Hoan, Louise Kautsky, Harry Laidler, Algernon Lee, Ramsey McDonald and Lillian Wald.
Arrangement
Arranged in 4 series: I. Correspondence; II. General Material; III. Second Donation; and IV. Photographs.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library holds a complete run of The Jewish Daily Forward.
Jewish Labor Committee Records (WAG.025)
Stephen Vladeck Papers (WAG.284)
Socialist Aldermen Papers (TAM.056.007)
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by May Vladeck Bromberg (daughter) in a series of gifts between 1963 and 1967. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 1967.004 and 1967.005. An additional three linear feet of material was donated in 1995 by Charney Bromberg (grandson). The accession numbers associated with this gift are NPA.1995.016 and NPA.1996.013. Amy V. Heinrich donated seven audio recordings in 2011. The accession number associated with this gift is 2014.106. The following accession number is also associated with this collection: NPA.2004.011.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Due to the fragile nature of the original materials, researchers must use the microfilmed version of Series I and part of Series II (boxes 1-8); microfilm call number is Film R-7325, Reels 1-20.
Public housing -- New York (State) -- New York; Jews |x Charities.; Manuscripts for publication.; Judaism and labor.; Jewish socialists -- United States.; Correspondence.; Jewish labor unions |z United States.; Socialism -- United States.; Press releases.; Minutes (administrative records); Clippings (information artifacts); Photographic prints.; Autobiographies.; Speeches.; Jewish Labor Committee (U.S.); Hoan, Daniel W. (Daniel Webster), 1881-1961; Laidler, Harry W. (Harry Wellington), 1884-1970; World ORT Union; Berger, Victor L., 1860-1929; Socialist Party (U.S.); Forṿerṭs (New York, N.Y.); Vladeck, B. (Baruch), 1886-1938; Asch, Sholem, 1880-1957.; Adler, Friedrich, 1879-1960; Berger, Meta Schlichting, 1873-1944; Kautsky, Luise Ronsperger, 1864-1944; Lee, Algernon; Wald, Lillian D., 1867-1940; McDonald, Ramsey; Bromberg, May Vladeck; Bromberg, Charney; Heinrich, Amy Vladeck
- Series I. Correspondence, 1912-1938
  Scope and Content Note
  This series is comprised of the correspondence files that Vladeck kept related to his professional and political activities and interests. Notable correspondents include: Friedrich Adler, Sholem Asch, Roger Baldwin, Otto Bauer, Victor and Meta Berger, Abraham Cahan, Albert Einstein, Daniel Hoan, Louise Kautsky, Harry Laidler, Fiorello La Guardia, Algernon Lee, Herbert H. Lehman, Meyer London, Ramsay McDonald, Tom Mooney, Paul Muni, Upton Sinclair, Norman Thomas, and Lillian Wald. In addition, for each letter of the alphabet (preceding the folders for named individuals or organizations), is a folder of general correspondence, "A", "B", etc. For the general folders there is a handwritten alphabetical list of some 500 names occurring therein, which is available upon request.
  Arrangement
  Folders are arranged alphabetically by name of individual, organization or subject, following the order apparently maintained by Vladeck himself or his clerical staff.
  Access Restrictions
  Entire series has been microfilmed. Researchers must use microfilm.
  - "A" GENERAL, undated (Box 1)
    General note
    Reel 1
  - ABRAHAM LINCOLN BRIGADE, 1937 (Box 1)
  - ABRAMOWITSCH RAPHAEL R., 1928-1937 (Box 1)
  - ADLER, CYRUS, 1929-1938 (Box 1)
  - ADLER, FRIEDRICH, 1926-1938 (Box 1)
  - ALDERMANIC CAMPAIGN, 1921 (Box 1)
  - SECOND ALDERMAN TERM, 1919-1921 (Box 1)
  - AMERICAN CIVIL LIBERTIES UNION, 1927-1937 (Box 1)
  - AMERICAN FEDERATION OF LABOR, 1927-1938 (Box 1)
  - AMERICAN HEBREW (The), 1932, 1934-1937 (Box 1)
  - AMERICAN JEWISH COMIITTEE, 1930-1938 (Box 1)
  - AMERICAN JEWISH CONGRESS, 1934, 1936-1937 (Box 1)
  - AMERICAN LABOR PARTY, 1937-1938 (Box 1)
  - AMERINGER, OSCAR, 1933, 1937 (Box 1)
  - AMERINGER, SIEGFRIED, 1937 (Box 1)
  - ANGLO-GERMAN NAVAL AGREEMENT, Jul 1935 (Box 1)
  - ANONYMOUS LETTERS AND WRITINGS, undated (Box 1)
  - ANTI-NAZI, 1933-1936 (Box 1)
  - ANTI-NAZI, 1937-1938 (Box 1)
  - ANTI-NAZI BOYCOTT, undated (Box 1)
  - ANTI-NAZI: KLEPPER, Dr. Otto, undated (Box 1)
  - APPLICATIONS AND REFERENCES, undated (Box 1)
  - APPRECIATION AND CRITICISM, undated (Box 1)
  - ASCH, ROSE, 1923, 1938 (Box 1)
  - ASCH, SHOLEM (and Nathan), 1928, 1935-1938 (Box 1)
  - AUSTRIAN AND LANCE - ATTORNEYS, undated (Box 1)
  - "B" GENERAL, undated (Box 1)
  - BALDWIN, JOSEPH CLARK, 1938 (Box 1)
  - BALDWIN ROGER, 1923, 1931, 1937 (Box 1)
  - BALLETTA FRANK - ATTORNEY, 1937 (Box 1)
  - BARONDESS, JOSEPH, 1923, 1938 (Box 1)
  - BAUER, CATHERIIE, 1938 (Box 1)
  - BAUER, OTTO, 1927-1929 (Box 1)
  - BEARAK, JOSEPH, 1929 (Box 1)
  - BERGER, VICTOR L., 1926-1931 (Box 1)
  - BERMAN, MORRIS, 1923, 1927, 1936 (Box 1)
  - BETH ABRAHAM HOME FOR INCURABLES, undated (Box 1)
  - BETH ISRAEL HOSPITAL, undated (Box 1)
  - BIALYSTOKER HOME FOR THE AGED, undated (Box 1)
  - BILLIKOFF, JACOB, 1925-1937 (Box 1)
    Reel 2
  - BILLINGS, WARREN, 1924, 1925 (Box 1)
  - BLANK, LEON, 1925-1929 (Box 1)
  - BLUMEN, ELIAS, 1929 (Box 1)
  - BLUMIN-KURSKY, FRANZ, 1929, 1932, 1937 (Box 1)
  - BOARD OF ALDERMEN, 1921 (Box 1)
  - BOOKS, undated (Box 1)
  - B'NAI B'RITH-BOGEN, BORIS etc., 1922-1938 (Box 1)
  - BREITNER, HUGO (Dr.), 1938 (Box 1)
  - BROMBERG, MAY AND NORBERT, 1930-1931 (Box 1)
  - BROOKLYN FORUM, undated (Box 1)
  - BROOKWOOD, KATONAH, NEW YORK, undated (Box 1)
  - BROWN, D., 1922 (Box 1)
  - BUND, undated (Box 1)
  - "C" GENERAL, undated (Box 1)
  - CAHAN, ABRAHAM, 1922-1934 (Box 1)
  - CHANIN, W.C., 1927-1928, 1938 (Box 1)
  - CHARNEY, C. KING, 1930-1937 (Box 1)
  - CHARNEY, MEREL, undated (Box 1)
  - CHARNEY, S., 1937 (Box 1)
  - CHEZKELS, HELEN, 1925-1928 (Box 1)
  - CHNEOUR, S., 1928, 1937-1938 (Box 1)
  - CITRINE, WALTER, 1935-1938 (Box 1)
  - CIVIC AFFAIRS, 1933, 1938 (Box 1)
  - CLINTON THEATER, 1937 (Box 1)
  - COHEN, MORRIS R., 1932, 1934, 1937 (Box 1)
  - CONGRATULATIONS COUNCIL, 1937 (Box 1)
  - COUNCIL, undated (Box 1)
    Reel 3
  - COUNCIL CAMPAIGN, 1937 (Box 1)
  - COUNCIL LEGISLATION, undated (Box 1)
  - COUNCIL ORGANIZATION, undated (Box 1)
  - COUNCIL - "PINS AND NEEDLES" PERFORMANCE, Mar 1938 (Box 1)
  - CRANK LETTERS, undated (Box 1)
  - "D" GENERAL, undated (Box 2)
  - DARTMOUTH COLLEGE, 1957 (Box 2)
  - DEBORAH JEWISH TUBERCULOSIS SOCIETY, 1924-1938 (Box 2)
  - DEWEY, JOHN, 1928-1934 (Box 2)
  - DUNBAR, ELIZABETH, 1916, 1925-1934 (Box 2)
  - DUNCAN, THOMAS U. (TOM), 1924-1937 (Box 2)
  - DWORKIN, DOROTHY, 1937-1938 (Box 2)
  - "E" GENERAL, undated (Box 2)
  - EAST SIDE VACATION CAMP - GENERAL, undated (Box 2)
  - EAST SIDE VACATION CAMP, 1925, 1927, 1930-1933 (Box 2)
  - EINSTEIN, ALBERT, 1932-1938 (Box 2)
  - EPSTEIN, LAZAR, 1925-1938 (Box 2)
  - "F" GENERAL, undated (Box 2)
  - FAMILY GENERAL, 1925-1938 (Box 2)
  - FAVORS GENERAL, 1924-1931 (Box 2)
  - FEDER, ANNA, undated (Box 2)
  - FEDERATION FOR THE SUPPORT OF JEWISH PHILANTHROPIC SOCIETIES, 1924-1937 (Box 2)
  - FOLKSZEITUNG-WARSAW, POLAND, 1928, 1938 (Box 2)
  - FORWARD GENERAL, 1921-1934 (Box 2)
  - FORWARD GENERAL, 1928-1938 (Box 2)
    Reel 4
  - FORWARD ADVERTISING, 1928-1930s (Box 2)
  - FORWARD AMA, undated (Box 2)
  - FORWARD ASSOCIATION, undated (Box 2)
  - FORWARD - BOSTON, 1928, 1935 (Box 2)
  - FORWARD BUSINESS, 1928-1938 (Box 2)
  - FORWARD - CHICAGO, 1928 (Box 2)
  - FOWARD EMPLOYEES, 1932-1933 (Box 2)
  - FORWARD - CONTRIBUTIONS TO LABOR ORGANIZATIONS, 1928, 1937 (Box 2)
  - FORWARD-LEGAL, 1928, 1938 (Box 2)
  - FORWARD-OTHER CITIES, 1928 (Box 2)
  - FORWARD-POLICY, 1928-1956 (Box 2)
  - FORWARD-WRITERS, CORRESPONDENCE, etc., undated (Box 2)
  - FREIE ARBEITER STIMME, undated (Box 2)
  - FRIENDS-GENERAL PERSONAL, undated (Box 2)
  - "G" GENERAL, undated (Box 2)
  - GERMAN JEWISH CHILDREN'S AID, undated (Box 2)
  - GLASSMAN FAMILY, 1923-1929 (Box 2)
  - GOCHGELERNT, G., 1935-1938 (Box 2)
  - GOLDSTEIN, JONAH J., 1928-1958 (Box 2)
  - GREEN, WILLIAM: AFL PRESIDENT, undated (Box 2)
  - GRUNDFEST FAMILY, 1921-1928 (Box 2)
  - "H" GENERAL, undated (Box 2)
  - HAGEN, PAUL, 1937 (Box 2)
  - HARRISON, CHARLES YALE, 1932, 1934, 1937-1938 (Box 2)
  - HEBREW HOME FOR THE AGED, undated (Box 2)
  - HEBREW SHELTER AND IMMIGRANT AID SOCIETY, undated (Box 2)
  - HERTZ, PAUL (Dr.), 1938 (Box 2)
  - HIRSCHMANN, I.A., 1929, 1936, 1938 (Box 2)
  - HOAN, DANIEL W., 1934, 1937, 1938 (Box 2)
  - HOME OF THE DAUGHTERS OF JACOB, 1922-1938 (Box 2)
  - HOUSING, undated (Box 2)
    Reel 5
  - HOUSING CORRESPONDENCE, 1931, 1934-1936 (Box 2)
  - HOUSING CORRESPONDENCE, 1934-1935 (Box 2)
  - HOUSING CORRESPONDENCE, 1934 (Box 2)
  - HOUSING CORRESPONDENCE, 1937 (Box 2)
  - HOUSING CORRESPONDENCE, 1937-1938 (Box 3)
  - HOUSING-LABOR HOUSING CONFERENCE, 1935-1936, 1938 (Box 3)
  - NEW YORK CITY HOUSING AUTHORITY - MEMORANDUMS, Mar 1934-Apr 1936 (Box 3)
  - NEW YORK CITY HOUSING AUTHORITY- MINUTES, Apr 25, 1931-Apr 9, 1935 (Box 3)
  - HOUSING-PRESS RELEASES, SPEECHES, AGREEMENTS, etc., 1921-1937 (Box 3)
  - HOUSING-REPORTS, etc., 1921-1937 (Box 3)
  - HOUSING STATISTICS, etc., undated (Box 3)
    Reel 6
  - HOUSING-WIILLIAMSBURG HOUSES, undated (Box 3)
  - HULL, CORDELL (Hon.), 1938 (Box 3)
  - HYLAN, JOHN F. (Hon.), 1921, 1923, 1925 (Box 3)
  - "I" GENERAL, undated (Box 3)
  - IMMIGRATION, 1921-1929, 1934, 1935 (Box 3)
  - IMMIGRATION, 1937-1938 (Box 3)
  - INVITATIONS-PRIVATE, 1921-1931 (Box 3)
  - INVITATIONS-PUBLIC, 1921-1938 (Box 3)
  - "J" GENERAL, undated (Box 3)
  - JAFFE, J., etc., 1912 (Box 3)
  - JEWISH CONSUMPTIVE RELIEF SOCIETY, 1921, 1928, 1938 (Box 3)
  - JEWISH LABOR COMMITTEE, 1934-1938 (Box 3)
  - JEWISH LABOR WORLD, undated (Box 3)
  - JEWISH QUESTIONS GENERAL, undated (Box 3)
  - JEWISH SOCIAL SERVICE ASSOCIATION, undated (Box 3)
  - JEWISH SOCIALIST VERBAND OF AMERICA, undated (Box 3)
  - JOINT DISTRIBUTION COMMITTEE: GENERAL, 1921-1938 (Box 3)
  - JOINT DISTRIBUTION COMIITTEE, 1937-1938 (Box 3)
  - JOBS, 1922-1938 (Box 3)
  - JOBS, 1932-1934 (Box 3)
  - "K" GENERAL, undated (Box 3)
  - KAHN, BERNARD (Dr.), undated (Box 3)
  - KARL, P., 1932-1934 (Box 3)
  - KAUFMAN, EDGAR J., 1938 (Box 3)
  - KAUTSKY, KARL AND LOUISE, 1927-1931, 1938 (Box 3)
    Reel 7
  - "KIDDUSH HASHEM" BY SHOLEM ASCH, undated (Box 3)
  - KOBRIN, LEON, 1937-1938 (Box 3)
  - KRITZER, HARRY, 1924-1926 (Box 3)
  - KUTLER, MORRIS D. [1], undated (Box 3)
  - KUTLER, MORRIS D. [2], undated (Box 3)
  - KUTLER, MORRIS D. [3], undated (Box 3)
  - KUTLER, MORRIS D. [4], 1930-1938 (Box 3)
  - "L" GENERAL, undated (Box 3)
  - LABOR STRIKES MINERS, 1928 (Box 4)
  - LAFOLLETTE, PHILIP F., 1931-1938 (Box 4)
  - LAFOLLETTE, ROBERT M., 1930 (Box 4)
  - LAGUARDIA, FIORELLO H., 1921-1937 (Box 4)
  - LANG, HARRY-HEARST ARTICLES, undated (Box 4)
  - LEAGUE FOR INDEPENDENT POLITICAL ACTION, 1929-1933 (Box 4)
  - LEAGUE FOR INDUSTRIAL DEMOCRACY, 1932-1938 (Box 4)
  - LEHMAN, HERBERT H., 1924-1938 (Box 4)
  - LEVICK, H., 1923-1937 (Box 4)
  - LEVITAN, SOLOMAN, 1931, 1937 (Box 4)
  - LITWACK A., 1923-1930 (Box 4)
  - LONDON, MEYER, 1916, 1926 (Box 4)
  - "M" GENERAL, undated (Box 4)
    Reel 8
  - MACDONALD, J. RAMSAY, 1927-1937 (Box 4)
  - MARSHALL, LOUIS, 1924-1928 (Box 4)
  - MCGRADY, EDWARD F. (Hon.), 1933-1937 (Box 4)
  - MEDEM, GINA, 1922-1927 (Box 4)
  - MEDEM SANITARIUM, undated (Box 4)
  - MEYERS, GEORGE F., 1929, 1938 (Box 4)
  - MILWAUKEE LEADER, undated (Box 4)
  - MINSKER YOUNG FRIENDS BEN. ASSOC., 1921, 1922, 1929 (Box 4)
  - MISCELLANEOUS, undated (Box 4)
  - MONTEFIORE HOME AND HOSPITAL, undated (Box 4)
  - MOONEY, TOM, 1930-1937 (Box 4)
  - MORRISON' HERBERT (Hon.), 1936-1938 (Box 4)
  - MORROW, FELIX, 1937 (Box 4)
  - MULLER, WILLI, 1935-1936 (Box 4)
  - MUNI, PAUL, 1928-1936 (Box 4)
  - "N" GENERAL, undated (Box 4)
  - NEW LEADER, 1924-1925, 1930-1937 (Box 4)
  - NEW SCHOOL, undated (Box 4)
  - NEW YEAR'S GREETINGS SENT, 1937-1938 (Box 4)
  - NEW YORK CITY, undated (Box 4)
  - NEW YORK TIMES, 1954, 1937 (Box 4)
  - "O" GENERAL, undated (Box 4)
  - OKUN, ISRAEL, 1927 (Box 4)
  - ORT GENERAL, 1928-1958 (Box 4)
  - ORT GENERAL, 1937-1938 (Box 4)
    Reel 9
  - "P" GENERAL, undated (Box 4)
  - PALESTINE, undated (Box 4)
  - PERETZ, M., 1923 (Box 4)
  - PERLMAN, SELIG, 1938 (Box 4)
  - PHILADELPHIA LABOR INSTITUTE, 1925-1926 (Box 4)
  - PIONEER YOUTH OF AMERICA, 1925, 1928 (Box 4)
  - POEM BY EDGAR ALLEN POE, undated (Box 4)
  - POLAND, undated (Box 4)
  - POSY, A. (Publisher), 1937 (Box 4)
  - PRIDE OF JUDEA CHILDREN'S HOME, undated (Box 4)
  - PUBLIC CORRESPONDENCE, 1929 (Box 4)
  - "Q" GENERAL, undated (Box 4)
  - "R" GENERAL, undated (Box 4)
  - RAND SCHOOL, 1925-1934 (Box 4)
  - RED HOOK HOUSING PROJECT, undated (Box 4)
  - REJEAN-KISIEL, SARA, 1935-1937 (Box 4)
  - ROOSEVELT, FRANKLIN D. (Hon.), 1930, 1936 (Box 4)
  - ROSEN, JOSEPH (AGRO-JOINT), 1925-1934 (Box 4)
  - ROSENFELD, JEROME, 1928-1938 (Box 4)
  - ROUMANIAN JEWISH AFFAIRS, undated (Box 4)
  - RUSSIA, undated (Box 4)
  - RYAN, GEORGE J. (Hon.), 1932-1934 (Box 4)
  - "S" GENERAL [1], undated (Box 4)
  - "S" GENERAL [2], undated (Box 4)
  - SARNOFF, DAVID, 1923-1933 (Box 4)
  - SCHLESINGER, BENJAMIN, 1929, 1931 (Box 4)
  - SCHNEYER, LOUIS A., 1922, 1925, 1926 (Box 4)
  - SCHOOL ADMISSIONS AND SCHOLARSHIPS, undated (Box 4)
  - SCHORSCH, JOHANN, 1936 (Box 4)
  - SCHWARTZ, MAURICE- YIDDISH ART THEATER, 1933-1937 (Box 4)
  - SCRIPPS-HOWARD NEWSPAPERS, undated (Box 4)
  - SECOND ALDERMAN TERM [See "A" Box 1], 1919-1921 (Box 4)
  - SETZER SAMUEL, 1929-1938 (Box 4)
  - SHERWOOD, ROBERT E., 1938 (Box 4)
    Reel 10
  - SHOHAN, ABRAHAM, 1932 (Box 4)
  - SICKNESS-CONDOLENCES, 1938 (Box 4)
  - SILVER, RABBI ABBA HILLEL, 1936-1938 (Box 4)
  - SILVERSTEIN, EDNA C. (Dr.), 1938 (Box 4)
  - SINCLAIR, UPTON, 1923-1937 (Box 4)
  - SINO-AMERICAN RELATIONS, 1931-1933 (Box 5)
  - SMITH, ALFRED E., 1925 (Box 5)
  - SOCIAL SERVICE GENERAL, undated (Box 5)
  - SOCIALIST PARTY, undated (Box 5)
  - SOCIALIST PARTY CAMPAIGN CONTRIBUTIONS, 1928 (Box 5)
  - SOCIALIST PARTY CAMPAIGN - CORRESPONDENCE, 1930 (Box 5)
  - SOCIALIST PARTY CAMPAIGN - FINANCIAL, 1930 (Box 5)
  - SOCIALIST PARTY CAMPAIGN - MISCELLANEOUS, 1930 (Box 5)
  - SOCIALIST PARTY CAMPAIGN-REPORT, 1934, 1937 (Box 5)
  - SOCIALIST PARTY DECLARATION OF PRINCIPLES, 1934 (Box 5)
  - SOCIALIST PARTY SPLIT, 1930-1935 (Box 5)
  - SOCIETY OF FRIENDS OF THE YIDDISH, undated (Box 5)
  - SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTE, undated (Box 5)
  - SOURCES, undated (Box 5)
  - STERN, ALFRED R., 1935-1938 (Box 5)
  - SUDARSEY, M. (Dr.), 1935-1938 (Box 5)
  - SULZBERGER, ARTHUR HAYS, undated (Box 5)
  - SULZBERGER, CYRUS L., undated (Box 5)
  - "T" GENERAL, undated (Box 5)
  - TCHARNY, DANIEL [TSCHARNY], 1928-1938 (Box 5)
  - TELUSHEIN, RABBI N., 1923-1938 (Box 5)
  - THEATER, undated (Box 5)
  - THIRD PARTY, 1924 (Box 5)
  - THOMAS, NORMAN, 1934-1938 (Box 5)
  - "U" GENERAL, undated (Box 5)
    Reel 11
  - UNIONS MISCELLANEOUS- AMALGAMATED CLOTHING WORKERS OF AMERICA, undated (Box 5)
  - UNIONS MISCELLANEOUS- BAKERY AND CONFECTIONERY WORKERS, undated (Box 5)
  - UNIONS MISCELLANEOUS- FURRIERS UNION, undated (Box 5)
  - UNIONS MISCELLANEOUS- INTERNATIONAL LADIES' GARMENT WORKERS' UNION, undated (Box 5)
  - UNIONS MISCELLANEOUS- INTERNATIONAL POCKET-BOOK WORKERS UNION, undated (Box 5)
  - UNIONS MISCELLANEOUS- MILLINERY WORKERS UNION, undated (Box 5)
  - UNIONS MISCELLANEOUS- UNITED MINE WORKERS UNION, undated (Box 5)
  - UNITED JEWISH AID SOCIETY OF BROOKLYN, undated (Box 5)
  - UNITED JEWISH APPEAL, undated (Box 5)
  - UNITED STATES DEPARTMENT CF LABOR, undated (Box 5)
  - UNIVERSITY OF PENNSYLVANIA, 1915 (Box 5)
  - "V" GENERAL, undated (Box 5)
  - VARDI-YOALIT THEATER STUDIO, undated (Box 5)
  - VLADECK-BUSINESS (PERSONAL), LEGAL, undated (Box 5)
  - VLADECK, B.C.-ANNIVERSARY, undated (Box 5)
  - VLADECK, B.C.-CONGRESSIONAL CAMPAIGN, undated (Box 5)
  - VLADECK, B C.-CORRESPONDENCE MISC., undated (Box 5)
  - VLADECK, B.C.-CORRESPONDENCE 1944, LIBERTY SHIP, undated (Box 5)
  - VLADECK, B.C.-FAMILY AND PERSONAL, undated (Box 5)
  - VLADECK, B.C. - 50th BIRTHDAY, undated (Box 5)